A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Buenos Aires, Argentina Field Office Files FA561
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Buenos Aires, Argentina Field Office Files
1959-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA561
1.31 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, Subject, and Personnel files.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
As received.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation maintained an office in Buenos Aires, Argentina from 1962-1975. Throughout the course of the Buenos Aires office's history, the Foundation's Argentina program focused on supporting projects and initiatives involved with science and technology, education, social science research and training, agricultural development, industrial and trade development, public and private management and administration, and population.
After the Foundation closed the Buenos Aires office in 1975, its Argentina programming became absorbed under its broader Andean Region and Southern Cone program aims. The Andean Region and Southern Cone office moved from Lima, Peru to Santiago Chile, in 1991.
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 January (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 February (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 March (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 April (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 May (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 June (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 July (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 August (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 September (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 October (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 November (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1972 December (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 January (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 February (Box 1)
- Chronological Correspondence, 1973 March (Box 1)
- Paraguayan Center of Population Studies (CEPED) -- Regional, 1972 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Attie, Silvia Regina, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Beckett, Vera J., 1962-1968 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Castellano, Luis, 1962-1974 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- de Cohan, Maria L.T., 1970-1972 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Cross, Cecil Harold, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Iglesias, Osvaldo, 1965-1972 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Jones, Silvia M., 1968-1969 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Logan, Diana, 1970 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Pasman, Marta, 1965-1973 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Pondal Rios, Silvia, 1968 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Reca, Lucio A., 1968 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Riofrancos, Marta S., 1959-1974 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Smith, Annette, 1965-1970 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- de Van Kregten, Roxane, 1970 (Box 1)
- Personnel -- Yrurtia, Alicia R., 1964-1970 (Box 1)